<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meta on Jiahe's Blog</title><link>https://blog.jiahe.dev/tags/meta/</link><description>Recent content in Meta on Jiahe's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 11:40:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jiahe.dev/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing Mastodon comments!</title><link>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/1740656457/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 11:40:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/1740656457/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been planning to add comments to my blog for a long time.
For the longest time now, I&amp;rsquo;ve just been posting to the void, not knowing if I missed anyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t like Disqus and storing comments in GitHub issues didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to me.
However, a recent wave of Hackernews articles about online discussions and a post about using Mastodon for comments have inspired me to explore that approach.
I like the idea of using a social media platform as a comments section because it feels like a place where discussions would organically take place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello Blog</title><link>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/1623987444/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 11:37:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/1623987444/</guid><description>&lt;p>Till now, I have been sharing my successes and completed projects on my portfolio at &lt;a href="https://www.jiahe.dev" target="_blank">https://www.jiahe.dev&lt;/a>, which you may want to take a look at. However, projects are never smooth sailing and some ideas have never seen the light of day. This blog is made for such projects, to document their progress regardless and for me to share my thoughts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On that note, a couple of long running projects I have had which I hope to showcase some time in the future are my audio effects platform and drone development and simulation project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/1623901051/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 11:37:31 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/1623901051/</guid><description>&lt;p>Orignally I had only planned for one Hello World post but because getting the blog up and running posed more of a challenge than initially expected, I&amp;rsquo;ll break it into two. This first post covers the process of creating the blog while the next will explain my rationale for creating the blog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I started off looking at some popular options for webpage design and hosting like Wix and Wordpress, especially because I had heard things about how popular Wordpress was and figured it was a good skill to learn. I was quickly turned away by the monthly costs however and decided to look for something else as I&amp;rsquo;m still at that point in time where I have much more time than money. I turned to GitHub Pages because it&amp;rsquo;s what I used for my portfolio, but I wanted to see if I could do a bit more.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>