<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web on Jiahe's Blog</title><link>https://blog.jiahe.dev/tags/web/</link><description>Recent content in Web on Jiahe's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 20:09:05 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jiahe.dev/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Little Miners Poc</title><link>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/1709726945/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 20:09:05 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/1709726945/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last Friday, I thought up a grand plan on how I could challenge the current state of mobile anime games.
The idea was that instead of gambling for pngs, you could pay to contribute to commissioning new character art.
This way, you&amp;rsquo;re guaranteed something for the money you put in, it benefits the entire player base and artists.
In a sense, I was hoping to centralize the exchange of money and services through an anime game I developed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>fwmcbaubau.com</title><link>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/1709531903/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 05:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/1709531903/</guid><description>&lt;p>Before we begin, check out the site at &lt;a href="fwmcbaubau.com">fwmcbaubau.com&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In case you didn&amp;rsquo;t visit the site or came from a future where the site is no longer live, here&amp;rsquo;s a brief description.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>fwmcbaubau.com is a website where users contribute to a global click count by clicking on a button which also plays an animation and audio.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="architecture">Architecture&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now that we&amp;rsquo;re on the same page, I&amp;rsquo;ll share the architecture of the site. The site itself is statically hosted, with the assets coming from a CDN.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sound Site Conception</title><link>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/1636209944/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 22:45:44 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/1636209944/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/Yi-Jiahe/soundsite" target="_blank">Sound site&lt;/a>, (read: sound sight), is a small project I worked on a bit in late June, exploring the &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Web_Audio_API" target="_blank">Web Audio API&lt;/a>. The idea was to make a easily accessible way for people to visualize sound and explore the effects of audio effects on the waveform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The basic idea of the Web Audio API is an Audio Routing Graph, which lives within an Audio Context. The graph is formed of individual Audio Nodes, of which there are three types, Sources or Inputs, Effects and Destinations or Outputs. Sources can be Oscillators which basically produce notes, Audio Recordings like files and Microphones. The Ouputs are basically the device speakers. Effects nodes can be compared to guitar effects pedals such as the DelayNode, DynamicsCompressorNode and GainNode. They do however, also provide functions like data analysis with the AnalyserNodes and other functions such as merging and splitting channels with the ChannelSplitterNode, ChannelMergerNode and audio spatialization.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>