<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Audio on Jiahe's Blog</title><link>https://blog.jiahe.dev/tags/audio/</link><description>Recent content in Audio on Jiahe's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 22:45:44 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jiahe.dev/tags/audio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sound Site Conception</title><link>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/sound-site-conception/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 22:45:44 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/sound-site-conception/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/Yi-Jiahe/soundsite" target="_blank">Sound site&lt;/a>, (read: sound sight), is a small project I worked on a bit in late June, exploring the &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Web_Audio_API" target="_blank">Web Audio API&lt;/a>. The idea was to make a easily accessible way for people to visualize sound and explore the effects of audio effects on the waveform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The basic idea of the Web Audio API is an Audio Routing Graph, which lives within an Audio Context. The graph is formed of individual Audio Nodes, of which there are three types, Sources or Inputs, Effects and Destinations or Outputs. Sources can be Oscillators which basically produce notes, Audio Recordings like files and Microphones. The Ouputs are basically the device speakers. Effects nodes can be compared to guitar effects pedals such as the DelayNode, DynamicsCompressorNode and GainNode. They do however, also provide functions like data analysis with the AnalyserNodes and other functions such as merging and splitting channels with the ChannelSplitterNode, ChannelMergerNode and audio spatialization.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello Blog</title><link>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/hello-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 11:37:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jiahe.dev/posts/hello-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>Till now, I have been sharing my successes and completed projects on my portfolio at &lt;a href="https://www.jiahe.dev" target="_blank">https://www.jiahe.dev&lt;/a>, which you may want to take a look at. However, projects are never smooth sailing and some ideas have never seen the light of day. This blog is made for such projects, to document their progress regardless and for me to share my thoughts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On that note, a couple of long running projects I have had which I hope to showcase some time in the future are my audio effects platform and drone development and simulation project.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>