<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Jiahe's Blog</title><link>https://yi-jiahe.github.io/blog/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Jiahe's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 11:37:24 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yi-jiahe.github.io/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hello Blog</title><link>https://yi-jiahe.github.io/blog/posts/hello-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 11:37:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://yi-jiahe.github.io/blog/posts/hello-blog/</guid><description>Till now, I have been sharing my successes and completed projects on my portfolio at https://www.jiahe.dev, which you may want to take a look at. However, projects are never smooth sailing and some ideas have never seen the light of day. This blog is made for such projects, to document their progress regardless and for me to share my thoughts.
On that note, a couple of long running projects I have had which I hope to showcase some time in the future are my audio effects platform and drone development and simulation project.</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://yi-jiahe.github.io/blog/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 11:37:31 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://yi-jiahe.github.io/blog/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>Orignally I had only planned for one Hello World post but because getting the blog up and running posed more of a challenge than initially expected, I&amp;rsquo;ll break it into two. This first post covers the process of creating the blog while the next will explain my rationale for creating the blog.
So, I started off looking at some popular options for webpage design and hosting like Wix and Wordpress, especially because I had heard things about how popular Wordpress was and figured it was a good skill to learn.</description></item></channel></rss>